Guide to the Memorial Library of Music: files, 1947-1953
Department of Special Collections
Nathan Van Patten Memorial Library of Music: files,
1947-1953
M0639
Van Patten, Nathan, 1887-1956.
2 linear ft.
Stanford University. Libraries. Dept. of Special Collections and University Archives.
Director of Stanford University Libraries, 1927-1947, Professor of Bibliography, 1948-1952, Professor Emeritus, 1952-1956, and Curator, Memorial Library of Music, 1952-1955. The collection contains primarily correspondence, accounts, provenance information, etc.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
None.
Provenance
Transfer from Memorial Library of Music, 1993.
Acquisition Information
Transfer from Memorial Library of Music, 1993.
Biography
Director of Stanford University Libraries, 1927-1947, Professor of Bibliography, 1948-1952, Professor Emeritus, 1952-1956, and Curator, Memorial Library of Music, 1952-1955.
Scope and Content
Contains correspondence, accounts, provenance information, etc.
Access Terms
The following terms have been used to index the description of this collection in the library's online public access catalog.
Barzun, Jacques, 1907-; Friedrich, Goetz.; Keating, George T., b. 1892.; Litvinov, Maxim, Mrs.; Menotti, Gian Carlo, 1911-; Milhaud, Darius, 1892-1974.; Montenezzi, Italo.; Rachmaninoff, Sergei, Mrs.; Ritchie, Ward, 1905-; Rodgers, Richard, 1902-; Sandberg, Mordecai.; Schatzki, Walter.; Schulhof, Andrew.; Schwarz, Kurt.; Schweitzer, Albert, 1875-1965.; Shostakovich, Dmitriéi Dmitrievich, 1906-1975.; Sibelius, Jean, 1865-1957.; Sterling, J. E. Wallace, (John Ewart Wallace), 1906-; Strauss, Richard, 1864-1949.; Stravinsky, Igor, 1882-1971.; Thompson, Virgil.; Tresidder, Donald Bertrand, 1894-1948.; Valle, Rafael Heliodoro, 1891-1959.; Winternitz, Emanuel.; Stechert-Hafner, Inc.; Music.; Memorial Library of Music.
Collection Contents
- Correspondence "A" (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Correspondence with the Accounting Department [1947-1953] (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Accounting Department: Budget Statements for the Department of Bibliography and the Memorial Library of Music [1951] (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Accounting Department: Budget Statements for the Department of Bibliography and the Memorial Library of Music [1952] (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Accounting Department: Budget Statements for the Department of Bibliography and the Memorial Library of Music [1953] (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Correspondence with Anderson and Ritchie (The Ward Ritchie Press) [1950] (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Correspondence with Anderson and Ritchie (The Ward Ritchie Press) [1951] (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Correspondence with Anderson and Ritchie (The Ward Ritchie Press) [1951] (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Correspondence with Anderson and Ritchie (The Ward Ritchie Press) [1952] (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Correspondence "B" (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Correspondence with Jacques Barzun (Columbia University) [1951-1952] (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Correspondence "C" (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Catalogue Proofs; Drafts for the "Acknowledgments" by van Patten (Box 1, Folder 13)
- Correspondence concerning the Sale of the Catalogue of the Memorial Library of Music [1951-1952] (Box 1, Folder 14)
- Correspondence "D" (Box 1, Folder 15)
- Correspondence "E" (Box 1, Folder 16)
- Correspondence "F" [among others, a letter by Goetz Friedrich] (Box 1, Folder 17)
- Correspondence "G" (Box 1, Folder 18)
- Correspondence "H" (Box 1, Folder 19)
- Correspondence with Otto Haas (Antiquarian Bookseller) [1945-1949] (Box 2, Folder 1)
- Correspondence "I" (Box 2, Folder 2)
- Correspondence "J" (Box 2, Folder 3)
- Correspondence "K" (Box 2, Folder 4)
- Correspondence with R. F. Kallir (International Autographs) [1948-1949] (Box 2, Folder 5)
- Correspondence with George T. Keating [1944] (Box 2, Folder 6)
- Correspondence with George T. Keating [1945] (Box 2, Folder 7)
- Correspondence with George T. Keating [1946] (Box 2, Folder 8)
- Correspondence with George T. Keating [1947/I] (Box 2, Folder 9)
- Correspondence with George T. Keating [1947/II] (Box 2, Folder 10)
- Correspondence with George T. Keating [1948/I] (Box 2, Folder 11)
- Correspondence with George T. Keating [1948/II] (Box 2, Folder 12)
- Correspondence with George T. Keating [1949/I] (Box 2, Folder 13)
- Correspondence with George T. Keating [1949/II] (Box 2, Folder 14)
- Correspondence with George T. Keating [1950/I] (Box 2, Folder 15)
- Correspondence with George T. Keating [1950/II] (Box 2, Folder 16)
- Correspondence with George T. Keating [1951-1953] (Box 2, Folder 17)
- George T. Keating: Check Lists for the Catalogue of the Memorial Library of Music [1948] (Box 2, Folder 18)
- List of Kin of those to whom the Catalogue of the Memorial Library of Music is dedicated. (Box 3, Folder 1)
- Correspondence with the Kin of those to whom the Catalogue of the Memorial Library of Music is dedicated [1951/I] (Box 3, Folder 2)
- Correspondence with the Kin of those to whom the Catalogue of the Memorial Library of Music is dedicated [1951/II] (Box 3, Folder 3)
- Correspondence with the Kin of those to whom the Catalogue of the Memorial Library of Music is dedicated [1951/III] (Box 3, Folder 4)
- Correspondence with the Kin of those to whom the Catalogue of the Memorial Library of Music is dedicated [1951/IV] (Box 3, Folder 5)
- Correspondence with the Kin of those to whom the Catalogue of the Memorial Library of Music is dedicated [1951/V (Box 3, Folder 6)
- Correspondence with the Kin of those to whom the Catalogue of the Memorial Library of Music is dedicated [1951/VI] (Box 3, Folder 7)
- Correspondence "L" [among others, letters to Mrs. Maxim Litvinov concerning Dmitri Shostakovich] (Box 3, Folder 8)
- Correspondence with the Library of Congress (Box 3, Folder 9)
- Correspondence "M" (Box 3, Folder 10)
- Correspondence with Gian-Carlo Menotti, Darius Milhaud and Italo Montenezzi [1947-1948] (Box 3, Folder 11)
- Correspondence with the Museum of Modern Art (Emanuel Winternitz) [1947-1949] (Box 3, Folder 12)
- Correspondence "N" (Box 3, Folder 13)
- Correspondence "O" (Box 3, Folder 14)
- Correspondence "P" (Box 3, Folder 15)
- Correspondence with Parke-Bernet [1947-1949] (Box 3, Folder 16)
- Publicity / News clippings (Box 3, Folder 17)
- Correspondence "Q" (Box 3, Folder 18)
- Correspondence "R" [among others, letters to Mrs. Sergei Rachmaninoff and Richard Rodgers] (Box 3, Folder 19)
- Correspondence "S" [among others, letters to Jean Sibelius, Richard Strauss and Mordecai Sandberg] (Box 3, Folder 20)
- Correspondence with Walter Schatzki (Box 3, Folder 21)
- Correspondence with Andrew Schulhof [1949] (Box 3, Folder 22)
- Correspondence with Kurt Schwarz (Antiquarian Bookseller) [1947-1948] (Box 3, Folder 23)
- Correspondence with Kurt Schwarz (Antiquarian Bookseller) [1949] (Box 3, Folder 24)
- Correspondence with Dr. Albert Schweitzer [1947/1952] (Box 4, Folder 1)
- Correspondence with the Scribner Book Store [1939-1953] (Box 4, Folder 2)
- Correspondence with Stechert-Hafner Inc. [1951-1952] (Box 4, Folder 3)
- Correspondence with Wallace Sterling [1950-1953] (Box 4, Folder 4)
- Correspondence with Stevens and Brown Ltd. [1947-1949] (Box 4, Folder 5)
- Correspondence with Igor Stravinski and related matters [1947-1948] (Box 4, Folder 6)
- Requisitions: Memorial Library of Music [1950] (Box 4, Folder 7)
- Requisitions: Memorial Library of Music [1951] (Box 4, Folder 8)
- Requisitions: Memorial Library of Music [1952] (Box 4, Folder 9)
- Correspondence "T" (Box 4, Folder 10)
- Correspondence with Virgil Thompson (Box 4, Folder 11)
- Correspondence with Donald B. Tresidder [1945-1947] (Box 4, Folder 12)
- Correspondence "U" (Box 4, Folder 13)
- Correspondence with the U.S. Government (Box 4, Folder 14)
- Correspondence "V" [Rafael Heliodoro Valle] (Box 4, Folder 15)
- Correspondence "W" - "X" (Box 4, Folder 16)
- Correspondence with William P. Wreden (Box 4, Folder 17)
- Correspondence "Y" - "Z" (Box 4, Folder 18)